DUNCAN SHEA

(805) 637-6741 | duncanshea@gmail.com | San Clemente, CA | linkedin.com/in/duncan-shea

PROFFSSIONAL PROFILE

I'm an experienced product and people leader with a strong background in technology. Empathetic, curious, and passionate about enabling people to build great products. I'm a problem solver and problem definer. I do my best work by creating a shared understanding of an opportunity, then driving collaboration and consensus around a vision. Excellent communicator across all levels in an organization.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Market Research | Customer Discovery | Establishing and Communicating Product Vision | Public Speaking | Financial Modeling

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Salesforce | SQL | Javascript | Ruby | Python | Git | NewRelic | JIRA | Snowflake | Asana | Trello | Figma | DNS | A11y

WORK EXPERIENCE

AppFolio, Inc. (Ticker APPF, \$4.25BN market cap, 2000+ employees, \$450MM revenue FY 2022. Ranked #1 on Fortune's list of Fastest-Growing Companies in 2020.)

Director, IM Websites & New Services | AppFolio Investment Management | Remote

Jun 2021 - Oct 2022

Responsible for launching and growing new products and services including Payments, Websites, and Asset Management.

- Increased Payments onboarding capacity from 10 to 40+ customers per month by identifying and removing onboarding and signup bottlenecks.
- Built the onboarding, maintenance and customer support playbook for Marketing Websites product. Reduced average onboarding time from 4 months to 40 days.
- Collaborated on a market research and customer discovery campaign that identified and defined a new product opportunity (Asset Management).

Director, Websites & AppFolio Premium Leads | AppFolio Property Manager | Remote

Feb 2020 - Jun 2021

As a product manager and business line owner, I was responsible for managing the P&L for Websites and Premium Leads products (~\$15MM combined annual revenue).

- Increased organic traffic to customer websites by 37% by launching a fully-integrated rental listing feed.
- Partnered with Data Science team to analyze customer usage of Premium Leads product, uncovering new insights and opportunities that led to targeted adoption efforts and a ~7% increase in monthly revenue.
- Reduced Accessibility-related support case volume by 50% by building and launching a transparent A11y layer in customer website tech stack.

Senior Manager, Value Added Services | AppFolio Property Manager | Santa Barbara, CA

Jul 2018 - Feb 2020

Owned all aspects of the Customer Website product, including the product roadmap, technical infrastructure and professional services functions. Led a team of 25 managers and individuals in engineering, onboarding and customer success roles.

- Identified limitations in technology underpinning customer websites, and migrated over 5500 customers to a new platform over a 6 month rollout with zero interruption to customers' businesses.
- Executed a price increase that doubled ARR from \$6MM to \$12MM, with negligible churn.
- Addressed scalability bottlenecks by building and launching a DNS management app for internal and external users.

Manager, Value Added Services | AppFolio Property Manager | Santa Barbara, CA

Jan 2017 - Jul 2018

- Built and led a team of 8 specialists responsible for technical support and maintenance of customer marketing websites.
- Decreased average case response time from 3 days to <24 hours by defining new team KPIs, implementing queue strategies to reduce chronic case backlog from 300+ to 0, and identifying and eliminating process bottlenecks.
- Established NPS tracking for this team maintained an average score of 80+, one of the highest in the company.

DUNCAN SHEA

WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Website Solutions Manager | AppFolio Property Manager | Santa Barbara, CA

Sep 2015 - Jan 2017

• Internal tech lead for the Website Production team, handling internal and external escalations around DNS, SEO, and general front-end code.

Web Production Specialist | AppFolio Property Manager | Santa Barbara, CA

Jul 2014 - Sep 2015

• Built marketing websites for AppFolio customers using Wordpress.

Self-Employed and Other Experience

Co-Founder | Amazing Grace Urns | Santa Barbara, CA & San Clemente, CA

2018 - Present

- My wife and I turned a service business (beautiful paper flowers for weddings, events, and interior design) into a product business (biodegradable cremation urns).
- We grew from \$1k to \$125k+ annual revenue in just 3 years, and handled everything from material sourcing, product design and manufacturing to website design, ecommerce systems, customer support and shipping.

Founder | SummerSignUp.com & BrightCamps.com | Santa Barbara, CA

2012 - 2014

- Designed, built, and launched a product to help local summer camps create their own online registration forms and accept credit card payments.
- Built on top of Wordpress (PHP and Javascript), Stripe API for payment processing.

Youth Program Director | Santa Barbara Youth Sailing Foundation | Santa Barbara, CA

2008 - 2010

Analyst | WMD Capital Markets LLC | Santa Barbara, CA

2007

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF ARTS | Political Science | UCLA Product Management Workshop | Marty Cagan

2004 - 2008 2019